<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Jonny Weapons</name>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="jonny-items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fabiovitalba/homebrew-aurora-index/main/homebrew-jonny/items/jonny-items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- Magic Weapons -->
	<element name="Shadow Steel Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_SHADOWSTEELBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>Another deadly invention, but not by gnomes, Shadow Steel is said to require souls to be produced. According to rumours, the souls are torn into pieces using dark spells and transformed into a raw spiritual essence of pain, which takes a pitch-black sheen reflecting no light. Weapons made from it cannot be resisted by conventional metals. They cut through the spiritual essence of living flesh, discharging excruciating pain into the victim. The rare survivors of these weapons report levels of pain that can render a person inert for hours.</p>
			<p class="indent">When weilding a weapon made of Shadow Steel, you have advantage on attack rolls made against any target wearing medium or heavy armour. A creature hit by a Shadow Steel Blade must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw, becoming stunned until the end of its next turn on a failed save.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="name-format">Shadow Steel Blade</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shield of Sboing" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_SHIELDOFSBOING">
		<description>
			<p>When wielding this shield you gain +2 to your AC, like with any normal shield. As a reaction you can redirect damage, form a melee weapon attack, back to the attacker and add 1d8 bludgeoning damage. You can use this feature 3 times per day. After that you need to make a long rest, to recharge the shield.</p>
			<p class="indent">Attunement: Once attuned to this shield, the bond can only be broken by sprinkling the blood of a blue midnight frog upon it while casting a Remove Curse spell. Being attuned means, that you can't use any other shield except this one, unless the attunement is broken.</p>
			<p class="indent">Curse: Whenever you use your reaction to redirect an attacks damage, you must roll a d20. If the result is 1, you suffer twice the reflected damage instead. If you should be reduced to 0 hit points, as a result of this damage, your soul will be trapped inside the shield.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="name-format">Shield of Sboing</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Death's Kiss (Legacy)" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_DEATHSKISS">
		<description>
			<p class="indent"><b>Base Item:</b> You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>1st Ritual Attunement:</b> The bow telepathically communicates with you, telling you "Kill those who've wronged you." in Elvish. In order to unlock this Tier, you have to deal a Killing Blow, using this Bow, to five (5) enemies that stand in your path of vengance. Doing so grants you the following ability:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Venomous Arrow:</b> Using an Action, you can imbue an arrow with a magical venom, that the bow applies. This venom remains on the arrow for 1 minute or until it hits a target. If a target is struck by this arrow, it must succeed in a DC 15 CON Saving Throw, or take 2d10 poison damage and be poisoned for 1 minute. Furthermore the target is knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>2nd Ritual Attunement:</b> ???. Doing so grants you the following ability:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Death's Kiss:</b> All arrows shot from this bow are enchanted with necromantic energies. When a target is struck by one of these Arrows, it is wounded. Any wounded target takes 1d4 necrotic damage for each wound they suffered. Afterwards they may make a DC 15 CON Saving Throw in order to end all the wounds effects. Alternatively a creature withing 5 feet of it may make a DC 15 WIS (Medicine) check to end the wound's effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longbow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Death's Embrace" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_DEATHSEMBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>This quiver always holds exactly 20 charges of silver arrows. When an arrow is taken from this quiver, a new arrow appears in it's place.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can draw any item the quiver contains as if doing so from a regular quiver or scabbard.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Magic Ammunition -->
	<element name="Vampire Tooth Arrow (Elder)" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_VAMPIRE_TOOTH_ARROW_ELDER">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow was crafted using the tooth of an elder Vampire. When used it counts as a magic weapon. If a creature is struck by this arrow it must make a DC 17 Constitution save. On a failed save it takes 2d10 necrotic damage, otherwise it just takes half of the damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="arrow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
