<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Jonny Weapons</name>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="jonny-items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fabiovitalba/homebrew-aurora-index/main/homebrew-jonny/items/jonny-items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- Magic Weapons -->
	<element name="Shadow Steel Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_SHADOWSTEELBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>Another deadly invention, but not by gnomes, Shadow Steel is said to require souls to be produced. According to rumours, the souls are torn into pieces using dark spells and transformed into a raw spiritual essence of pain, which takes a pitch-black sheen reflecting no light. Weapons made from it cannot be resisted by conventional metals. They cut through the spiritual essence of living flesh, discharging excruciating pain into the victim. The rare survivors of these weapons report levels of pain that can render a person inert for hours.</p>
			<p class="indent">When weilding a weapon made of Shadow Steel, you have advantage on attack rolls made against any target wearing medium or heavy armour. A creature hit by a Shadow Steel Blade must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw, becoming stunned until the end of its next turn on a failed save.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="name-format">Shadow Steel Blade</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shield of Sboing" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_ITEM_WEAPON_SHIELDOFSBOING">
		<description>
			<p>When wielding this shield you gain +2 to your AC, like with any normal shield. As a reaction you can redirect damage, form a melee weapon attack, back to the attacker and add 1d8 bludgeoning damage. You can use this feature 3 times per day. After that you need to make a long rest, to recharge the shield.</p>
			<p class="indent">Attunement: Once attuned to this shield, the bond can only be broken by sprinkling the blood of a blue midnight frog upon it while casting a Remove Curse spell. Being attuned means, that you can't use any other shield except this one, unless the attunement is broken.</p>
			<p class="indent">Curse: Whenever you use your reaction to redirect an attacks damage, you must roll a d20. If the result is 1, you suffer twice the reflected damage instead. If you should be reduced to 0 hit points, as a result of this damage, your soul will be trapped inside the shield.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="name-format">Shield of Sboing</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
