<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Jonny Feats</name>
		<update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="jonny-feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fabiovitalba/homebrew-aurora-index/main/homebrew-jonny/classes/jonny-feats.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Vampire - Undead Form" type="Feat" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_CLASSES_FEATS_VAMPIRE_UNDEADFORM">
		<prerequisite>Dexterity 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[dex:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite: Dexterity 13 or higher</i></p>
			<p>Since you've been infected with the Vampire pleague, you gain the following benefits</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your Dexterity score increases by 2 and your Charisma score increases by 1, to a maximum of 16.</li>
                <li>Your creature type changes to undead. Spells and abilities that state effects or conditions specifically regarding Undead of a specific CR have no effect on you.</li>
				<li>If a spell or ability other than your own would cause you to gain Hit Points, you gain that many temporary Hit Points instead. If you are reduced to 0 hit points and fall unconscious as a result, any healing you receive will stabilize you and leave you on 1 hit point and unconscious.</li>
				<li>Furthermore, you cannot die from old age and you do not require air, food or drink.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your creature type changes to undead.
			If a spell or ability other than your own would cause you to gain Hit Points, you get temporary Hit Points instead.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Vampire - The Sanguine Curse" type="Feat" source="Homebrew (Jonny)" id="ID_HB_JONNY_CLASSES_FEATS_VAMPIRE_THESANGUINECURSE">
		<prerequisite>Dexterity 13 or higher</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[dex:13]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite: Dexterity 13 or higher</i></p>
			<p>The sanguine curse has taken a hold on you. As a result you gain the following features:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You cannot enter a residence you do not own without an invitation from one of the occupants. If you enter a residence involuntarily such as being dragged into one, you take 1d10 psychic damage at the start of your turn while you are inside it.</li>
                <li>You gain Darkvision (60 ft.) if you do not already have it.</li>
				<li>While in sunlight, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.</li>
				<li>You must feed every 7 days.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You cannot enter residences you don't own. You also have disadvantage on rolls, while in sunlight.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
